

MARY KASPARIAN FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+1 219 309 7225



kasparian.mary@gmail.com





mary-kasparian



Chicago, Illinois

EDUCATION

2021 - Present

Front End Development -Software Engineer Launch School/Skillcursh

2012 - 2014

Masters in Science **DePaul University**

2007 - 2011

Bachelors in Science Butler University

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Detail

Problem Solver

Oriented

Organizational

Team Work

skills

Time

Adaptability

Management

DEVELOPER SKILLS

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

React

PROFILE

Passionate front-end web developer with a background in science. I use JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, and React to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for client-side web applications. Having worked in science research in a variety of different labs has provided me with the analytical and problem solving skills, necessary for adapting quickly to new ever-changing environments.

EXPERIENCE

2022 - PRESENT SKILLCRUSH / LAUNCH SCHOOL

STUDENT WEB DEVELOPER

Student developer that has taught myself to code over 3 years. Have been a student at Bloc, Skillcrush. Currently a part time student at Launch School as I continue my education.

2019 - 2022 NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

RESEARCH TECHNICIAN II

Ran chromatin extractions and ChIP experiments for both modERN and ENCODE projects. Performed and validated 1000 cell transfections over multiple cell lines and designed and generated 600 CRISPR constructs

2014 - 2019 UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO

RESEARCH TECHNICIAN

Worked on ENCODE project - maintained stable transfections and validated W(Tiesas) cells. Design, production, and validation of CRISPR/Cas9 plasmids

QUALIFICATIONS

- · Able to code web pages from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React. Along with working proficiency of the Git version control, Wordpress control management, command line (Mac & Linux), and FTP procedures.
- · Fundamental understanding of mobile first design concepts, cross browser development, API implementation and search engine optimization
- 10+ years of science research experience granted me the ability to easily communicate with fellow collaborators and developers to establish the necessary requirements to meet milestones and complete projects in a professional and timely manner.